[
  {
    "question": "What is the complexity of inserting an element at the beginning of an array?",
    "optionA": "O(n)",
    "optionB": "O(1)",
    "optionC": "O(logn)",
    "optionD": "O(0)",
    "answer": "O(n)"
  },

  {
    "question": "What's the complexity for accessing the first inserted element within a stack?",
    "optionA": "O(n)",
    "optionB": "O(1)",
    "optionC": "O(logn)",
    "optionD": "O(ct)",
    "answer": "O(n)"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which is a correct initialization of a pointer to a FILE?",
    "optionA": "FILE* pFile = fopen(filepath, filemode);",
    "optionB": "FILE* pFile = openfile(filename);",
    "optionC": "FILE* pFile = openfile(filename, filemode);",
    "optionD": "FILE* pFile = fopen(filename, filemode);",
    "answer": "FILE* pFile = fopen(filename, filemode);"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the size of a pointer to char?",
    "optionA": "4 Bytes",
    "optionB": "1 Byte",
    "optionC": "8 Bytes",
    "optionD": "2 Bytes",
    "answer": "4 Bytes"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which format specifier is used to display a double value?",
    "optionA": "%s",
    "optionB": "%d",
    "optionC": "%f",
    "optionD": "%lf",
    "answer": "%lf"
  },

  {
    "question": "A pointer which points to a simple linked list element is?",
    "optionA": "4B on the stack and sizeof(nodeType) in the HEAP",
    "optionB": "8B on the stack",
    "optionC": "sizeof(nodeType) on the stack",
    "optionD": "sizeof(nodeType) on the stack and 4B in the HEAP",
    "answer": "4B on the stack and sizeof(nodeType) in the HEAP"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the size of an int?",
    "optionA": "8 Bytes",
    "optionB": "4 Bytes",
    "optionC": "2 Bytes",
    "optionD": "32 Bytes",
    "answer": "4 Bytes"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the output of this statement\n \"printf(\"%d\", (a++))\"?",
    "optionA": "The value of (a + 1)",
    "optionB": "The current value of a",
    "optionC": "Error message",
    "optionD": "Garbage",
    "answer": "The current value of a"
  },

  {
    "question": "What does this declaration mean? int x : 4;",
    "optionA": "X is a four-digit integer",
    "optionB": "X cannot be greater than a four-digit integer",
    "optionC": "X is a four-bit integer",
    "optionD": "None of the above",
    "answer": "X is a four-bit integer"
  },

  {
    "question": " How many times will the following loop execute?\n for(j = 1; j <= 10; j = j-1)  ",
    "optionA": "Forever",
    "optionB": "Never",
    "optionC": "0",
    "optionD": "1",
    "answer": "Forever"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is a loop construct that will always be executed once?",
    "optionA": "for",
    "optionB": "while",
    "optionC": "switch",
    "optionD": "do while",
    "answer": "do while"
  },

  {
    "question": "How many instances of a class can be declared?",
    "optionA": "1",
    "optionB": "10",
    "optionC": "As per required",
    "optionD": "None of the answers",
    "answer": "As per required"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following is invalid?",
    "optionA": "''",
    "optionB": "\"\"",
    "optionC": "'a'",
    "optionD": "'abc'",
    "answer": "'abc'"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following symbol is used to denote a pre-processor statement?",
    "optionA": "!",
    "optionB": "#",
    "optionC": "~",
    "optionD": ";",
    "answer": "#"
  },

  {
    "question": "What is the valid range of numbers for int type of data?",
    "optionA": "0 to 256",
    "optionB": "-32768 to +32767",
    "optionC": "-65536 to +65536",
    "optionD": "No specific range",
    "answer": "-32768 to +32767"
  }
]
